And now for my report if I may.
We just received word of the
Emperor of Earthwold's sudden passing.
"Crown Prince Wein Salema Arbalest,
Kingdom of Natra"
And there is now a power struggle
within the imperial palace.
"Crown Prince Wein Salema Arbalest,
Kingdom of Natra"
The emperor's charisma is
what propelled the empire forward.
"Ninym Ralei, Aide to the Crown Prince,
Kingdom of Natra"
But the brighter the light,
the deeper the darkness that follows.
"Ninym Ralei, Aide to the Crown Prince,
Kingdom of Natra"
It will be even darker if
they failed to name a successor.
There is unrest within the empire
and the kingdoms surrounding us.
However, we are...
Or should I say, here in Natra,
we are graced with a beacon of hope.
Prince Wein, that would be you,
Your Highness.
But it's not just me.
You liegemen who supported
my father all these years
are also a beacon of hope.
Your Highness.
We are not worthy of such words.
As long as we stand united
toward the same goal,
there is no challenge we can't overcome.
That earlier matter with the
imperial ambassador proves it.
It is just as you say, Your Highness.
Your Highness, what a
magnificent man you've become.
Nothing else to report?
Nothing more.
Then I thank you. You're dismissed.
Your Highness!
I can't wait to sell off this kingdom!
You're also a beacon of hope?
As long as we stand united
toward the same goal?
I didn't mean a word of it!
No way in hell can I get this
kingdom out of the mess it's in!
Ain't gonna happen! No way, no how!
You shouldn't keep saying such things,
even if you're joking, Wein.
I never said I was joking, Ninym!
I'm totally serious!
That's even worse.
You grow lazy the moment
you know no one's watching.
You must try a little harder.
Huh? What's with the poindexter act?
Ninym, even you know how dirt poor
this kingdom is in every possible way.
We're a petty kingdom
with no more than 500,000 subjects.
And in the continent's far north,
spring is short, and winter is long.
Plus, most of our territory
consists of barren rock and mountains.
There's no money to invest
in domestic development,
our meager resources mean
we can't raise capital,
and we have no industries of value.
And that's putting it lightly.
We're a weak little kingdom that
could be wiped off the map in a flash.
And now my old man's fallen ill,
and I gotta run things.
I can't take it anymore!
I can't wait to sell
this kingdom and disappear.
But to do that,
first I gotta strengthen Natra.
The greater a nation's value,
the higher the price it will fetch.
That will affect how cushy
my retirement life will be!
Yeah, yeah, I'm sick of hearing
that harebrained plan.
There are other things
you should be worrying about.
"Princess Falanya Elk Arbalest,
Kingdom of Natra"
Dear Brother, sorry to bother
you when you're so busy.
"Princess Falanya Elk Arbalest,
Kingdom of Natra"
Do you have a moment?
Of course.
Is something the matter, Falanya?
I just saw Father and wished
to inform you of his condition.
I see.
Father is looking much better.
He even felt ready to take a walk today.
That's great news.
But let's hold off on
that walk a bit longer.
How come?
The neighboring kingdom of Marden
is poised to invade Natra at any moment.
What? Are you saying...?
We're going to war.
Marden was once on par with Natra
until a newly discovered gold mine
allowed their kingdom to rapidly expand.
However, their current king is unpopular.
But you already know that.
Yes.
I learned he is served
by corrupt officials
who ignore his failures and reaffirm
his belief that he's an enlightened ruler.
He is creating a vicious cycle that
will drive his kingdom into the ground.
That's why their king is looking
for an easy win to distract his people.
And our kingdom fits the bill
now that the imperial forces
that were stationed here are gone.
But you won't let them do that, will you?
I overheard the military officers
talking in the inner courtyard.
What did they say?
"Now is the time for the swords of
Natra to fulfill their appointed task!"
And, "As liegemen, we must live up
to the prince's expectations."
Stuff like that!
Did they really?
You heard them, too, right, Nanaki?
"Nanaki Ralei, Falanya's Bodyguard"
Yes, they wouldn't shut up.
Oh no, are those idiots getting
all excited at the thought of battle?
Are they raring to go?
Do they have any idea how
expensive it is to wage war?!
Brother?
I'll pray for your victory.
That's all I can do.
May you defeat our foes!
Y-Yes, thanks.
We'll launch a half-hearted attack
and then sue for peace.
Natra's forces number
6,000 against Marden's 7,000.
Your Highness.
Both armies are arrayed on the field.
Now we wait for the battle to begin.
Yes, Your Highness.
And I was hoping
you might have some words for the troops.
Battles wear down more
than a soldier's body.
They also take a toll on his soul.
Would you not give them a
few words to boost their morale?
Though they've been trained by the empire,
their tension is palpable,
for this is their first real battle.
Torace of Heinoy.
Your spear is upside down.
Forgive me, Your Highness!
Karlmann, Patess,
Livi, Logli.
It's not that funny.
Yes, Your Highness!
That eased the tension a bit.
Until this day, Natra's army has
been looked down on as weak.
It may have been true at one time.
Marden's army likely
looks down on us, too.
But I know the truth.
You have survived
the most grueling training.
I know that you possess a noble
courage that is beyond compare.
And I know that as you face our invaders,
a flame imperishable burns in your hearts.
Therefore, you can no longer
be seen as weak by any measure.
Now prove it in battle!
Show them that we are
the dragon of the north!
Let it resound across the continent!
We are the most formidable force of all!
Today is the day we fight
and rewrite history!
That was magnificent.
At least they won't be so nervous
that they lose hold of their weapons.
Did you plant those soldiers
you addressed by name?
Don't be silly. I was winging it.
We're not an empire with
hundreds of thousands of troops.
Natra only has about 10,000
if you add them all up.
Hear me, brave warriors of Marden!
Natra's troops are
but lowly foot soldiers!
They mistake recklessness for courage
and are now trying to thwart
our advance like the fools they are.
But there is no way in hell
these northern peasants
can defeat our army of elite troops!
Trample them underfoot!
Stain this wasteland red with their blood!
Stand ready, men!
Ready...
Attack!
I have a report, Your Highness!
Marden's troops are in a
center-heavy formation!
We'll break through their center,
then turn and crush them from behind!
In that case, we'll stand our ground!
They'll break upon our defensive line.
The Mardenian army
won't know what hit them!
Hey, hey, hey!
W-Wait a second. What is happening?
General Urgio! Our left flank
is requesting reinforcements!
Sir! Sanse Company was decimated!
Tology Company is moving to fill the void!
General! Our right flank
is in dire straits, too!
What the hell?! How can these
Natran troops be so formidable?!
How can Marden be so weak?!
What is going on? How can
we possibly be kicking their butt?
What's with Marden's tactics?
It's not a schoolyard brawl!
Meanwhile, our troops are dominating.
Is there a problem, Your Highness?
No. It's just I'm surprised by how
fiercely our troops are fighting.
Has it all not gone as you planned,
Your Highness?
I remember that day you met
with the imperial ambassador.
Ambassador Brandel.
"Ambassador Fisch Brandel,
Empire of Earthwold"
I view maintaining relations
with the empire as my top priority.
As such, should we not bridge the divide
between the Imperial Army
and Natra's Royal Army?
I concur, Your Highness.
What I propose is this.
Would you not provide the Imperial Army's
expertise and funding to our Royal Army?
Who would ever believe
they would accept such a request?
But Ambassador Brandel did accept it.
That means we've adopted the methods of
the continent's greatest military force.
And now that our military has
tapped the empire's abundant capital,
it's grown more powerful before our eyes.
Natra's army is more than a match
for any petty kingdom that has
only experienced limited skirmishes.
Ideally, Marden will cut
their losses and run, but...
Your Highness! The center
of our line is under pressure!
The morale of our forces
is starting to fray.
Crap!
After all that training?
Even after rigorous training
and your inspiring words,
Natra's troops are not mentally
prepared for a real battlefield.
The chill air, splattering blood,
and wanton slaughter consume them.
The tide turns against us.
Please don't notice.
Natra's forces are
no longer pressing the attack.
Their strength is but a facade.
Order the commanders of
both flanks to enter the fray
and stop the enemy dead in their tracks!
And have our forces in
the center reform their lines!
We strike once they are ready!
What's the target?
The head of their leader!
Oh, crap!
He noticed.
Your Highness, we must fall back now.
I know.
General! They're fleeing from their camp!
Pathetic. It's better
to fall bravely in battle.
Take them from behind
before they can hide in the hills.
Damnit. How did this happen?
Quickly, men, turnabout!
They've accepted their fate!
Archers, loose!
This is looking like a complete victory!
Wh-What's this?!
An ambush?!
They're attacking!
Defend General Urgio with your lives!
Pathetic.
Why you...!
You're the general, I take it?
Surrender now, and you
may survive with prompt treatment.
Surrender? Surrender, you say?
To hell with that!
I'm the general of Marden's army!
I'm not gonna surrender to some woman,
and a lowly, dirty Flahm at that!
So be it.
Take his head and
raise it high for all to see.
And see that his last words
are never heard again.
Yes, ma'am.
The enemy general died in
silence as far as I'm concerned.
This battle's pretty much over.
Yes, indeed.
Now what the hell am I supposed to do?
Now that we've crushed
the Mardenian invaders,
Eastern Marden is utterly exposed!
We should turn the tables
and invade at once!
We could carve off a
large chunk of their territory!
I agree.
Our swift victory means we still
have plenty of troops and supplies.
Your Highness!
What is your command?!
I can't believe this!
Do they have any idea how risky it is
to invade without carefully planning?!
But how can I possibly say that now?
Now that we've utterly
crushed Marden's army,
weak-kneed words will cause my generals'
loyalty to crash down like an avalanche.
And that can only end in a coup d'etat!
I didn't want to do this,
but I've got no choice.
I hear what you're saying.
You're correct in saying our great victory
has put tremendous momentum behind us.
That is why I propose this.
As you know, ours is a barren,
unprosperous land.
But the same can be said of Marden.
And its eastern region
has few strategic points.
Based on our current troop strength
and places within our grasp,
there is a location worth taking.
The Jilaat Gold Mine.
If we're to capture anything,
it should be that.
Yes! That's the reaction I wanted.
After all, targeting
their gold mine is crazy talk!
No matter how much strategic value it has,
attacking without much intel
and with troops weary from battle
would be fruitless, futile, feckless.
But it has stoked a serious debate.
The gold mine is impossible,
so they need another target.
But where? Does Eastern Marden
have another location
with the strategic value of the mine?
No! No, it doesn't!
There are no other targets of value!
The other possibilities are worthless.
The moment they realize that,
their thirst for conquests will vanish.
They may think a bit less of me
for making a ludicrous proposal,
but I'm used to it!
And it'll be totally worth it
if they decide to withdraw!
Your Highness.
Here it comes!
Well? Tell me my proposal is crazy talk.
They want to tell me how reckless it is,
but they don't know how.
I gotta think of a way for
my officers to preserve their honor
by acting like their wisdom
struck deep into my soul.
If I do that, everything will be--
I am in awe of your intellect.
What?!
It is just as you say, Your Highness.
The Jilaat Gold Mine
is the only target of worth!
This is, indeed, a surprise.
I can hardly believe that your Highness
knew of our long-standing plan
to take the gold mine.
I'm absolutely speechless.
Wait, what?!
While we were celebrating our victory,
Your Highness must have been
studying the feasibility of our plan.
I'm humbled by your foresight.
Your Highness, we'll set out
at once upon your command!
Let us strike the gold mine
while the iron's hot!
--Your Highness!
Your Highness!
Ninym, help.
Sorry. Nothing I can do.
The invasion of Marden is a done deal.
I could've nixed the plan if
our army hadn't won by a landslide.
So what now, Wein?
I don't wanna think about it.
I can't even.
You know that's not an option.
It's not?
No, it's not.
Okay, I'll think of something
if you meow like a cat.
Well, come on then!
Cat got your tongue, Ninym?
Has curiosity killed your inner cat?
Too proud to channel your inner feline?
Fine. Meow.
So, what's the plan?
Let's see.
We should start by verifying
the intel on the mine's defenses.
Then we should reassess our supply lines
and do our best to maintain troop morale.
We can take the mine before Marden
can mount an adequate defense.
But that's all easier said than done.
Meow.
I know. It's back-to-back battles
after the Polta Highlands.
We're bound to stumble somewhere.
But that stumble is just what we
need to convince our army to withdraw.
Now we wait for that to happen.
Right.
Meow.
Well, that didn't work.
We actually took the mine.
We actually took it.
Come on, meow for me.
I'm so over that.