Thanks to you,
all of Mealtars' people were
able to escape unharmed.
I would like to express my gratitude
to you both on their behalf.
Helping the oppressed is the
greatest wish of the Teachings of Levetia.
We are delighted we could
save them from the empire's tyranny.
How did you end up as
Mealtars' representative?
That is a rather long
and complicated story.
But this gentleman is their mayor,
and I have his consent.
If I may, I have a question for you.
Your army so graciously defended us,
but what will they do now?
Is it not obvious? They will drive back
the princes' armies and free the city.
Is that not right, King Gruyere?
Yes, that was the plan.
We cannot thank you enough.
We escaped the city unharmed
thanks to the threat of your host.
But to fall further into your debt
could only be deemed ungracious of us.
What would you do if you removed
yourselves from our protection?
We will reclaim the city by our own hand.
To that end, we would like to purchase
your army's excess weapons and food.
We'll pay triple the going price.
Now, let's see what they say.
You wish to buy our excess supplies?
Of course, I am well aware that
you act according to God's divine will.
As such, your holy army will not
be swayed by money.
However, Mealtars is a mercantile city,
and coin is the traditional
symbol of good faith.
Please allow us to pay you.
Once we retake the city,
we shall erect a monument
and temple in praise of your deeds.
Now that the Levetians have
30,000 refugees under their wing,
their options must be limited.
I imagine they'd like
to return home at once, but...
You are offering us coin and renown
if we leave you weapons
and food and return home?
He is a marvel. He truly is.
That move was far beyond
all my expectations.
So, Prince Wein,
I must refuse you for that very reason.
How delightful. I'd love to play
with this boy some more.
I would deny him, frustrate him,
and then poke and prod the wound.
I want to see how
he reacts after that and--
We accept.
What?
King Gruyere, what did you just say?
I said I accept his proposal, Caldmellia,
Director of the Bureau of Teachings.
Am I not the one responsible
for this decision?
I have the military under my charge.
As such, I say this:
We should accept his proposal.
He will likely create a militia
from the people of Mealtars.
Once the imperial princes
are worn down by battle,
he'll urge them to negotiate.
We could press the matter and
have Mealtars fight alongside us,
but I have no intention of getting
caught up in your capricious actions.
We will only sell our surplus supplies.
Our army stays put until we confirm
that your people have retaken the city.
I've no objections.
I thank you from the bottom of
my heart for your cooperation.
I have a report for His Highness!
What?! The people of Mealtars
have taken up arms?!
Yes, Your Highness! They're armed
and are coming down the hill!
The people have been
organized into a militia,
but can they repel my brothers' armies?
The princes see Mealtars' people
as the goose that lays golden eggs.
They won't want to fight because
the more they kill, the less they profit.
Plus, the Levetian army is
still unscathed and in reserve.
Send a message to Manfred at once!
Now for the final touch.
Lowa, ask the princes
to gather for a meeting.
Wait, not that trick?
Yep, it's the go-to move
at times like these!
You know who's behind
the assassination attempt?!
Yes.
Don't tell me you're
accusing Bardloche and me?
I couldn't stop thinking about it.
Why would the assassin do such a thing?
Care to explain?
Security in the city was airtight.
Plus, private guards were
placed at each compound.
It's hard to believe an assassin could
succeed under such circumstances.
But there is one likely suspect.
It's neither me nor
anyone else in this room.
Don't tell me...
That's right! This was all
the work of Prince Demetrio!
That is the truth behind this crime.
That's absurd!
Why would he do such a thing?!
Mealtars' standing suffered
when it fell under suspicion,
and both of your forces
were weakened in the fighting.
If he were to return and attack you,
he could claim Mealtars and the throne.
Then Prince Demetrio would be victorious.
I have no doubt that Demetrio never
intended for the summit to succeed.
That's why he was not
receptive to our discussions
and kept pressing his claim to the throne.
Don't tell me it's all...
...getting pinned on Demetrio.
That's right. The failed summit,
the assassination attempt,
the war, the bad weather tomorrow,
and everything under the sun!
We'll pin it all on Demetrio!
And there it is.
Wein's patented trial in absentia.
Mealtars knows this was not
a fight either of you sought.
As such, we are prepared
to pay sufficient compensation.
And we shall refrain from pursuing any
future relations with Prince Demetrio.
If I reject their proposal,
Manfred will likely agree to it.
If I reject their proposal and
Bardloche and I take Mealtars,
we'll still end up
fighting over the throne.
That will only end up
benefitting Demetrio.
He alone will claim victory.
Very well, then.
I agree to your proposal.
I knew you two would be on board!
I am afraid we have caused you
much needless trouble.
Think nothing of it.
It was a wonderful opportunity
to build strong ties with Mealtars.
Pinning the blame on Demetrio
will take the wind out of his sails.
The same goes for my brothers'
forces surrounding the city.
As a result,
Mealtars is now firmly
ensconced in my faction.
Of course, I am well aware that the hearts
of your people lie with you, not me.
This has made me realize something.
The measure of a sovereign
is more than just strength.
I asked Prince Wein a question before
our talks with King Gruyere and company.
I said, "Why have you been so eager
to work together with Mealtars?"
What did he say?
Falanya has taken a shine to your city.
What big brother wouldn't want his
little sister to return home triumphant.
To think it was all to gladden
the heart of his little sister.
I'm amazed he would wager his
fate along with our city's just for that.
Sheesh. I guess I'm not
used to laughing that hard.
Let's try that a--
Enough already.
What's the point of straining
your voice for something so dumb?
Chances like this don't come too often.
I don't see anything wrong
with enjoying the moment.
Well, I do understand how you feel.
I never expected our exports to be such
a success and fuel a booming economy.
If we continue to prosper, the people
will rejoice, and our budget will grow.
We'll have more options,
and the kingdom's value will rise.
Talk about too much of a good thing!
I see a cushy life ahead
in my princely future!
Wasn't long ago you were carrying on about
retiring and selling off the kingdom.
Retire? Sell off the kingdom?
I don't know what you're talking about!
I'll indulge in every possible luxury
while milking my current
position for as long as I can!
I'm impressed by how far revenue
from the Marden region has grown.
I know! It's all thanks to my bright idea!
"Marden"    "Natra"
By swearing allegiance to Natra,
"Natra"
"Mardenian region"
By swearing allegiance to Natra,
"Earthwold Empire"
Marden now has access to an
abundance of goods from the east.
But the nations of the west won't
welcome such commerce with open arms.
The Levetians view the continent's
eastern half as barbarian territory.
They're even prejudiced
against the east's goods.
That's why I've conspired with Marden
to falsify the land of origin.
We're exporting the empire's
products as if they were Natra's!
It's a revolutionary idea!
The venture has been a jackpot,
greatly enriching Marden's coffers.
It's tough being such
a genius. It really is!
But if this keeps up,
Marden's economy will
rival ours in less than ten years.
Worst case, they'll declare independence.
We can't let that happen.
We need to find another
major trading partner.
Enter.
Excuse me, Highness.
An envoy has just arrived
from the Kingdom of Soljest.
From Soljest?
I'll be right there.
Show them to the audience chamber.
Highness!
Soljest? What do you suppose
King Gruyere wants?
I just thought of a great plan.
Prince Wein is to visit Marden?
Yes, it seems His Highness was invited
to a ceremony in the Kingdom of Soljest
and would like to
visit our land on his way.
The prince is no doubt concerned
about the future of Marden
as a vassal state of Natra.
Understood. Let us put His Highness's
mind to rest by showing our allegiance.
Yes, but Marden is now
in a prime position.
This is a chance to redress
the disparities in our relationship.
We may even be able
to extract some concessions.
Tell me, Jiva, what sort of concessions
do you think we should extract?
Marriage between you, Lady Zenovia,
and His Highness, Prince Wein.
With negotiations in Soljest near at hand,
he'll no doubt avoid a clear answer.
But it would be in our best interests to
extract a commitment while he is here.
If such a marriage comes to pass,
it will boost Marden's standing in Natra
and greatly expand our influence.
But only if I can become his bride.
Does it bother you that much?
I'd like to muss it up, to say the least.
No, the color will come off.
I already told you.
What about my princely prerogative?
No means no.
So, about what you said.
Do you really intend to wed Zenovia?
As if. I'd like to stay single for now.
Why?
I want to enjoy having all sorts of ladies
begging for my hand in marriage.
I was joking!
Don't worry. I won't break it.
The title of queen consort
is a useful negotiating tool
--if we keep it up for grabs.
--That's true.
So, the purpose of this visit
is to see whether Marden intends to
adopt a cooperative attitude toward Natra.
And if they are cooperative,
they're almost guaranteed
to demand that I wed Zenovia.
In turn, I will do everything
to evade the issue.
You are just plain awful.
I bid you welcome.
You are too gracious, Marchioness Zenovia.
Your Highness, there is
no need to stand on ceremony.
Zenovia alone will suffice.
Then with your permission, Zeno...
...via.
Boobies!
No, you idiot!
Focus with all your strength!
I was shocked the first time
I heard about it.
To think you would import imperial goods
and market them as Natran made.
It was all for the benefit of the good
and godly people of the west.
I simply got a bit creative.
Zenovia, rapid growth may
sometimes be a source of stress.
I would be happy to discuss
any concerns you might have.
Well, since you mentioned it,
the Kingdom of Delunio sent a letter
of protest regarding trade goods.
From Delunio?
So Marden also received that letter.
So you did, too?
Yes, it was a complaint
about our trade goods.
Their kingdom is extremely conservative.
And their king is quite young,
so most political matters are handled
by their prime minister, Sirgis.
He is quite patriotic and a fervent
follower of the Teachings of Levetia.
He seeks to preserve his kingdom's culture
while casting out foreign influences.
As such, he likely
harbors resentment toward us.
Keep the goods flowing.
Are you sure?
He can't be that serious
if he merely sent a letter.
Don't take him seriously
until there is a line of envoys
protesting outside your door.
All right, I will do that.
Wait. Is that all she has to say?
When I asked if she had any concerns,
I thought she'd mention the disparities
in our kingdom and bring up our marriage.
That's what I was banking on, at least.
You were so sure
she'd ask you to marry her.
Then you were supposed
to coolly brush her off.
She'll have to make some
kind of move tomorrow!
I bet she'll drop a hint
during the tour of the city!
Let's hope they don't think
you suffer from an inflated ego.
That's the one thing I want
to avoid for the sake of my honor!
I am honored to see you again,
Your Highness.
Zeno, may I ask how
you serve the marchioness?
I am one of Lady Zenovia's attendants.
I watch over the city and handle
other affairs in milady's stead.
Today, she asked me to tell you
to please enjoy the tour of our city.
I bet she'll try to break the ice
while she shows me around.
Now then, shall we begin?
The bronze statues in our central plaza
were erected as a symbol of Marden's
desire for peace and prosperity.
Our land has yet to fully heal
from the recent war.
But all of us hope that we have
finally achieved a lasting peace.
Have no fear.
Marden will continue to thrive
as long as the economy is booming.
Economic power means you can
ward off outside interference.
And as you grow strong, you can join
your neighbors in a bid for independence.
Is that not an eventual
option open to you?
Surely you jest?
Lady Zenovia and her vassals
are happy to be a part of Natra.
We believe that is the best way
to assure Marden's prosperity.
I see.
So she intends to maintain a
cooperative relationship with Natra.
In that case...
Shall we take a break?
There is a bench over there.
Here it comes! She's going
to broach the subject of marriage!
What do you think of our city?
The sights were magnificent,
as is the energy of your people.
Seeing it firsthand made me realize
how much they are counting on you.
Indeed. My support continues
to grow as the economy booms.
A good relationship between rulers
and their people never hurts.
But you can never rest easy.
I have always wanted to ask you.
Why is Your Highness
so wary of the people?
Wary?
Well, maybe wary isn't
really the right word.
Perhaps "oddly distant" is better.
Well...
...let me ask you this.
Are noble and royal bloodlines venerable?
What? Of course they are!
Everyone believes that they are.
Then let me ask you this.
At what point do you think
they became venerable?
I'm not sure I follow.
For instance, I am a member
of the Natran royal family.
If noble and royal bloodlines are
venerable, when did I become so?
When you were born?
Right.
Those born of a venerable bloodline
will also be of venerable blood.
So then, when did
my father become venerable?
When he was born, of course,
just like Your Highness.
Exactly.
Children born of royalty are venerable
because their parents are, too.
And their parents, too, are venerable,
and so on down the line.
It's simple logic.
So then, Ninym.
If we traced my bloodline back through
history, where would we end up?
Caleus, a chief disciple of Levetia,
founder of the Levetian religion.
Right.
However, he was but a humble farmer
until Levetia found him.
His parents were, too.
So back to that question.
At what point did Caleus's
bloodline become venerable?
Once he started following Levetia
and accomplished many great deeds?
Precisely.
By virtue of their brains,
their brawn, or even plain luck,
commoners can distinguish
themselves and gain renown.
If you trace back through
all venerable bloodlines,
you'll always end up at a commoner.
What does that have
to do with my question?
In short, all nobility and royalty,
even the most haughty,
were commoners
if you trace all the way back.
That means even those despised
as commoners today
can become nobles or even royalty one day.
Now back to your first question.
Why am I wary of the people?
Natra is home to some 800,000 people.
There are that many nameless yet
potential royals watching my every move.
How could I live like
that without being wary?
I suppose that's why many royals
try to create mythologies
surrounding their families.
What's the matter?
Nothing really. It's just, I am once again
overwhelmed by how great a man you are.
Pay it no mind.
A great man?
I'm glad you think so,
but I'm not feeling
very great at the moment.
Why is that?
Truth be told, a wedding proposal
I'd expected never materialized.
And so I started to think
that maybe I had an inflated ego.
I know not whom you speak of.
But if it is a certain Mardenian,
she is too busy with the affairs of state.
I believe marriage would be unthinkable.
B-But if she married me, those affairs
that make her busy would vanish.
Wouldn't that be handy?
While that may be true,
she may also have a shallower reason.
A shallower reason?
For instance, Your Highness's face
is not her type. Things like that.
No, that was simply a jest.
W-Well, it's about time we get back.
Let us return to the palace.
The light at this time of day gives
a whole different look to the city.
My face isn't her type.
Stupid inflated ego!
Let it go, already. It was
spur-of-the-moment subterfuge.
I'm entering hibernation. See you later.
You're impossible.
Forgive me, Jiva.
I disregarded your idea of marriage.
The prince seems distant and a bit scary.
So then Prince Wein is like a
sort of hero to you, Lady Zenovia.
Yes, that is painfully apparent
when I speak with him.
And it reminds me that I could
never be queen to such a great man.
I know that such a marriage
would be a clever move.
Passing it up means I failed as a leader.
You need not wed His Highness
if your heart is in doubt.
Take comfort in knowing your vassals
shall help you find the best way forward.
Thank you.
It is our duty.
Milady!
What is it?!
Delunio's prime minister
is at the front gate!
Sirgis is here?!